Guide to the Arboretum at Connecticut College Records, 1890-2016 (inclusive), 1930-1990 (bulk) RG51
Linda Lear Center for Special Collections and Archives
- Series VI: Undergraduate Natural Science Studies, 1954-1996
  - Bachelder, Karen – "Vegetation Analysis of Seven Sites in the Connecticut Arboretum", 1983 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Ballek, Robert W. – "The Migration, Orientation, and Homing of Ambystoma Maculatum to a Connecticut Arboretum Breeding Pond", 1973 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Barrett, Nels – "The Ecological Effect of Windthrows upon a Forest Community", 1977 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Barrett, Nels – "The Connecticut Arboretum Winter Bird Census", 1977 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Barrett, Nels – "A Comparative Study of Seven Field Surveys in the Connecticut Arboretum", 1978 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Bazer, Laurence – "A Comparison of Vigilance Rate between Birds in Mixed Foraging Flocks and Solitary Foragers in the Connecticut Arboretum", 1983 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Bohan, Susan and Paula McDonald – "Fall Competition between Vegetarian Waterfowl", 1983 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Brauner, David M. – "Territory Competition and Oviposition Site Availability in the Dragonflies Sympetrum rubicundulum and Aeshna clepsydra", 1991 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Brawley, A. Hunter – "An Analysis of the Stopover Ecology of Neotropical Migrant Landbirds", 1993 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Brown, Bobbie – "A Study on the Vegetation Changes within the Connecticut College Arboretum", 1974 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Brown, Elizabeth – "Vegetation Development: Old Field and Forest", 1981 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Butcher, Gregory S. – "Effects of Vegetational Changes and Urbanization on Breeding Birds of the Connecticut Arboretum, 1953-1976", 1977 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Butcher, Gregory S. – "Equilibrium Biogeography and the Size of Nature Preserves: An Avian Case Study", 1980 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Bystry, Jane – "A Study of Vegetation in a Shallow Pond", 1973 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Carr, Clara – "Secondary Successional Trends in the Connecticut Arboretum", 1958 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Carroll, Margaret A. – "Size Related Foraging Behavior of Bumblebees (Bombus) Specializing on Impatiens capensis", 1983 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Cave, Scott – "The Effects of the Meadow Vole (Microtus pennsylvanicus) on the Salt Marsh Ecosystem", 1990 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Christman, Priscilla – "The Effects of Burning on the Soil Microorganisms of an Andropogon Field and an Oak-Hardwoods Forest", 1970 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Coleman, Wendy – "A Study of the Rock Dynamics in the Bolleswood Natural Area of the Connecticut Arboretum, Spring and Summer 1975", 1977 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Cook, John – "Thames Science Center Trail Guide", circa 1980 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Crispe, Helen T. – "The Effect of Burning on the Microorganisms in the Soil of an Andropogon Field and an Oak-Hardwoods Forest", 1971 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Crispe, Helen T. – "The Possibility of Allelopathic Control as a Stabilization Factor in Thicket Communities", 1972 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Currie, Robert M. – "A Brief Survey of the Connecticut Arboretum Pond", 1976 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Cutler, Pam – "Plant Succession: A Study of the Vegetation around a Small Pond in the Arboretum", 1973 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - de Fuccio, Elise – "Soil Fauna Density and Diversity", 1981 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - deLaforcade, Susan – "Pollination and Nectar Stealing by Bombus vagans, B. impatiens, and Apis mellifera on Jewelweed (Impatiens capensis)", 1991 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Delaney, Ross – "A Palynological Study of North Arboretum-Bolles Road Bog in New London, Connecticut", 1978 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Elsbree, Mary – "Soil-Vegetation Analysis of Transect I and II – The Natural Area", 1959 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Evans, Tim – "Wetlands of the Connecticut Arboretum: Vegetation and Soils Analysis", 1987 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Ferm, Judy – "Postburn Soil Temperatures in a Deciduous Forest: A Study in Microclimates", 1976 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Field, Elizabeth – "The Effect of Fire on an Oak-Birch Forest", 1974 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Flynn, Alison – "Integrated Pest Management in the Connecticut College Greenhouse", 1992 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Foster, D. – "Twenty years Vegetation Development on Three Area in the Connecticut Arboretum", 1977 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Gans, Hilary – "Effects of Fire on Invertebrates in Old Fields Maintained by Controlled Burning", 1986 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Goodman, Laurie – "Small Mammal Population: Census and Study", 1981 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Goodwin, Cait – "Foraging Behavior of Bumblebees on Jewelweed", 1989 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Hine, Pamela and Frances Kay – "The Pollination of Jewelweed", 1981 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Hine, Pamela – "Mamacoke Tidal Marsh: Quantitative Comparison of Vegetation Composition, 1957 and 1975", 1983 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Hitchcock, Diane – "Orientation of Ambystoma maculatum to and from a Breeding Pond", 1975 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Hogeland, Amy – "Microscopic Life of a Pond", 1976 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Hokkanen, Joel and Todd Maguire – "The Biological Control of Whiteflies (Trialeurodes vaporariorum) with Encarsia formosa and Delphastus pusillus", 1993 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Howell, Penelope – "A Study of the Microtus pennsylvanicus Populations Native to the Tidal Marshes on Mamacoke Island", 1975 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Johnson, Loretta CIRCA – "Old Field Biotic Development and Forest Dynamics in the Connecticut Arboretum", 1979 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Jones, Gary S. – "Hemlock Reproduction in the Bolleswood Natural Area", 1977 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Kitchel, Donna A. and Daniel Polidoro – "Animal Ecology Project", 1989 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Kluza, Daniel – "The Breeding Success of Red-eyed Vireos (Vireo olivaceous) in the Connecticut College Arboretum", 1991 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Lepore, Susan – "Algae in the Arboretum Pond", 1974 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Littlefield, M. – "Report on Gastropod Analysis: Mamacoke Cove", 1982 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Lombardi, Maura, David Tyler, and Ruth Haas – "Competition in Microtus pennsylvanicus and Peromyscus leucopus", 1982 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Loutrel, Elizabeth D. – "Determination of the Age and Life History of Mountain Laurel in the Connecticut Arboretum Natural Area", 1967 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Low, Bill – "Lichens of the Connecticut Arboretum (photo study)", 1975 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Macmillan, Alison – "The Changes in Vegetation of the Connecticut College Arboretum Bog from 1953-1977", 1978 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Manthorne, Arthur E. – "Six Study Sites in the Connecticut Arboretum: A Comparison and Trends", 1979 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Marcus, Ilene – "Matthies Tract Burn Study", 1991 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Markow, Joseph – "Distribution of Color Morphs of Red-Backed Salamanders Phlethodon cinereus, in the Connecticut College Arboretum", 1993 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Masciale, Mary Ellen – "Trends in Vegetation Development: Studies in the Connecticut Arboretum", 1981 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - McCarthy, Christine M. – "Prescribed Burning in the Avery Tract of the Connecticut Arboretum", 1975 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - McCarthy, Katharine A. – "The Physiognomic Changes of Vegetation Development from Old Field to Forest in the Connecticut Arboretum", 1980 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - McDonnell, Mark – "A Technique for Measuring Temperatures at the Cambium during a Prescribed Burn", 1973 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - McDonnell, Mark – "The Possible Role of Allelopathy as a Stabilizing Factor in Gaylussacia baccata clones: A Preliminary Report", 1974 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - McGlathery, Karen J. – "Old Field Biotic Development in the Connecticut Arboretum", 1981 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Meehan, Charles A. – "A Study of Vegetative Dynamics in the Connecticut Arboretum", 1977 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Mercaldo, Renee and Bart Haskins – "The Effects of Prescribed Burning on Small Mammal Populations", 1983 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Morton, S., J. Graham, and G. Biddle – "Summary of Documentary Research (Bolles Farm)", 1976 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Newman, Beverly – "The Vegetation and its Development in the Connecticut College Arboretum, New London, Connecticut", 1980 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Newman, Sarah – "Land Level as it Affects Salt Marsh Vegetation", 1973 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - O'Brien, Maria – "The Effect of the Mute Swan (Cygnus olor) on a Native Duck Population", 1983 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Padro, Maria, Laura Tseng, and Laura Williams – "Foraging Behavior in Two Ant Species: Formica fusca and Harpagoxenus americanus", 1991 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Pearsall, Scott – "Seasonal Variation of Morphological Traits and Flight Metabolism in Drosophila melanogaster", 1990 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Pearsall, Scott – "Small Mammal Population in Small and Large Forests: A Pilot Study", 1991 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Pfanner, Karen – "Old Field Ecosystem", 1974 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Philbrick, Margarett and Polly Le Boutillier – "Vigilance and Foraging Efficiency in Four Insectivorous Participants of Mixed Flocks", 1982 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Philbrick, Margarett – "Forest Fragmentation and its Effect on Breeding Birds in Southeastern Connecticut: The Preliminary Results of a Regional Study", 1984 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Pitt, William – "Prey-Capture of Sheet-Web Spiders in the Connecticut College Arboretum", 1989 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Platz, Barbara – "Preliminary Checklist of Vascular Plants Found in the State Wildlife Sanctuary, New London, Connecticut", 1962 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Rice, Barbara – "Primary Succession in the Connecticut Arboretum Natural Area (Eastern Section)", 1954 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Robbins, Marcia—"A Brief Survey of the Use of Pesticides and Insecticides and Related Horticultural Practices in Ornamental Landscape in Eight Locations as Related to the Caroline Black Garden", 1967 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Robbins, Nick and Rich Peterson – "The Wigwam: A Dwelling for All Seasons", 1990 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Roberts, Daniel – "Study of Peat, Plant, Plant, and Soil Solution Iron in Six Connecticut Salt Marshes for Spartina patens, Juncus gerardi, Distichlis spicata, and Spartina alterniflora, Short and Tall", 1975 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Rolland, Alma – "A Population Study of the Painted Turtle, Chrysemys picta, in the Connecticut Arboretum", 1977 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Rosenbaum, Kim and David Knox – "Oral History: The Bolles Farm", 1976 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Rowe, Helen – "Lichens as Indicators of Air Pollution Levels", 1974 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Schwartz, Josh – "Vegetation Changes in the Connecticut College Arboretum Bog", 1974 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Shelburn, Jeanne – "Matthies Tract: Old Field Development", 1973 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Siewers, Kristine – "Naturalistic Landscaping in the Connecticut Arboretum: A Demonstration and Practical Application of Selective Herbicide Treatment", 1977 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Smith, Michael and Daniel Love – "The Effects of Fire on Insect and Spider Populations", 1991 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Smultea, Mari Ann – "A Population Study of Microtus pennsylvanicus and Peromyscus leucopus in an Old-Field Habitat", 1984 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Stark, J. Marshall – "Size Related Differences in Foraging Behavior of Bumblebees (Bombus) Foraging on Impatiens capensis", 1984 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Stark, Wendy – "The Analysis of Seeds Recovered though Flotation at the Mamacoke Cove Prehistoric Site", 1982 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Sutphen, Eunice E. – "Three Decades of In Situ Vegetation Change on a Post-Agricultural Site in the Connecticut Arboretum at Connecticut College", 1988 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Tabachnick, Joan – "Vegetational Development in the Abandoned Fields of the Bolleswood Natural Area of the Connecticut Arboretum at Connecticut College", 1977 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Thomas, David and Daniel McCarthy – "Small Animal Census in the Arboretum Field", 1983 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Thompson, Louise – "A Study of Vegetation Patterns", 1980 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Tucker, Lauren – "Vegetation Studies of the Connecticut Arboretum Bog", 1978 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Tweedie, Susan – "The Relationship of Mountain Laurel to the Distribution of Windthrows on Mamacoke Island", 1976 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Veitch, Betsy – "Ecological Study of the Avery Cove Marsh, Connecticut Arboretum", 1967 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Waller, Jeffery D. – "Vigilance and Foraging Efficiency in Large and Small Flocks of Black-Capped Chickadees", 1984 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Warga, Pamela – "Analysis of the Old Field Ecosystem", 1969 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Wheeler, Laurene – "Removal of Various Species of Fruits by Avian Dispersers", 1986 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Wheeler, Laurene – "Oriental Bittersweet: Avian Dispersal during the Winter in Relation to Other Species of Fruiting Plants", 1987 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Wilson, John – "Vegetation Studies at Selected Sites in the Connecticut Arboretum, Spring 1976" (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Woodman, Tom – "A Brief Look at a Saltmarsh on Mamacoke Island, CT", 1974 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Zaprzalka, Joan – "Bird Ecology: A Project", 1975 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Zaprzalka, Joan – "A Study of the Winter Bird Population of the Connecticut Arboretum", 1976 (Box 15, Folder 21)
- Series VII: Audio and visual material, ca. 1920-2009
  This series contains film, photographs, negatives, slides, and reel-to reel tape documenting the arboretum, staff, faculty and students and other natural areas in Connecticut. Also documented well is the effects of the 1938 hurricane on the campus and New London. This series contains some digital material; please consult archivist for access. See also Campus Photograph Collection, Arboretum series.
  - Aerial photographs: arboretum and campus (31 photographs, 10 negatives), circa 1940-1982 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Aerial photographs: arboretum infra-red (12 polaroid), 1972 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Aerial photographs: campus (4 photographs, 4 negatives), 1973 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Aerial photographs: campus (4 photographs, 4 negatives), 1973 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Arboretum historical footage circa 1931 to the 1940s; DVD and digital files available. See archivist for access (0:40 :27 minutes), 2006 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Bolleswood and hemlocks (13 photographs, 11 negatives), circa 1920-1937 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Bolleswood natural area, (56 photographs, 17 negatives) (1 of 3 ), circa 1950-1985 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Bolleswood natural area, (56 photographs, 17 negatives) (2 of 3 ), circa 1950-1985 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Bolleswood natural area, (56 photographs, 17 negatives) (3 of 3 ), circa 1950-1985 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Caroline Black Garden arboretum (12 photographs, 3 negatives), circa 1966-1967 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - College campus views, 1953-1965 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Controlled burns (14 photographs), Circa 1979-1988 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Controlled burns: Glenn Dreyer photos, Matthies tract William Niering And Department of Environmental Protection fire crew (10 photographs), 1983 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Controlled burns: Glenn Dreyer photos, plots A (Matthies tract) and forest plot (Avery tract), Spring (9 photographs, 2 negatives), 1985 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Controlled burns: Matthies tract (11 photographs, 4 negatives), 1967-1985 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Controlled burns: Matthies tract, field and forest burns (12 photographs, 6 negatives), 1984 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Controlled burns: National Science Foundation burn studies (13 photographs, 7 negatives), 1968-1970 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Controlled burn and Arboretum Pond, (41 photographs) (1 of2 ), 1985 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Controlled burn and Arboretum Pond, (41 photographs) (2 of 2), 1985 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Creighton, Harriet (Botany professor) correspondence: re: slides includes inventory and history, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Creighton, Harriet slides: arboretum (13 slides), 1938-1939 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Creighton, Harriet slides: campus views (1 of 2 )( 54 slides), 1937-1939 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Creighton, Harriet slides: campus views (2 of 2 )( 54 slides), 1937-1939 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Creighton, Harriet slides: Caroline Black Garden (9 slides), 1938-1940 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Creighton, Harriet slides: Commencement and Spring Sing (10 slides), 1939 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Creighton, Harriet slides: Connecticut College flower shows (20 slides), 1939-1940 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Creighton, Harriet slides: groups of people (15 slides), 1937 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Creighton, Harriet slides: Harkness Chapel (12 slides), 1938-1939 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Creighton, Harriet slides: hurricane aftermath Connecticut College (26 slides), 1938 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Creighton, Harriet slides: hurricane aftermath New London (37 slides), 1938 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Creighton, Harriet slides: ice storm (32 slides), 1940 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Creighton, Harriet slides: Larabee Oak and Harkness estate (5 slides), 1936-1937 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Creighton, Harriet slides: New London views (15 slides), circa 1936-1939 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Creighton, Harriet slides: Yale-Harvard crew races (11 slides), 1940 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Dreyer, Glenn photographs: litter removal, controlled burn plots, Gypsy moth defoliation of Avery Tract (20 photographs), 1982 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Event: civic planting conference, Connecticut Arboretum, June 23 (13 photographs, 12 negatives), 1949 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Event: civic planting conference, Connecticut Arboretum, June 23 (13 photographs, 12 negatives), 1981 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Event: civic planting conference, Connecticut Arboretum, June 23 (13 photographs, 12 negatives), 1981 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Event: civic planting conference, Connecticut Arboretum, June 23 (13 photographs, 12 negatives), 1981 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Event: final day of Girl Scout day camp in Arboretum August 14 (6 negatives), 1947 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Event: garden club dedication of Demarst Memorial, September 21 (12 negatives), 1950 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Event: Wetland Art exhibit (4 photographs), 1979 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Experiment: Gallows Lane spraying (12 negatives), undated (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Experiment: spraying experiments (11 negatives), 1949, 1951 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Experiment: tree painting and land purchase shots tract 11, Ribaudo, 1951 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - General: staff, students, and event (17 photographs), 1931-1948 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - General: staff, students, and faculty (13 photographs,1 negative), staff1953-1981 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - General: staff, students, and faculty (13 photographs,1 negative), 1953-1981 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - General: staff, students, and programs (27 photographs, 1 negative ), 1930-1975 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - General: students in arboretum (7 photographs, 5 contact sheets), 1988 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - General unidentified arboretum photographs (15 photographs, 7 negatives), 1949-1957 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Richard Goodwin's slides; includes views of campus, Groton, and New London and the ice storm (26 slides), 1952-1964 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Hurricanes: Hurricane Gloria (19 photographs, 2 negatives), 1985-2009 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Hurricanes: 1938 Hurricane, (8 photographs, 4 negatives, 4 glass lantern slide) (1 of 2) (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Hurricanes: 1938 Hurricane (8 photographs, 4 negatives, 4 glass lantern slide) (2 of 2) (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Images for publication (8 photographs, 4 negatives), 1950-1996 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Lake [i.e. pond] and surrounding area (23 photographs, 6 negatives, 2 postcards), 1938-1985 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Lake in snow, William Niering photographs (10 photographs, 5 negatives), 1953 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Laurel walk and outdoor theater (15 photographs, 4 negatives, 1 printout), circa 1933-1985 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Mamacoke tract (46 photographs, 26 negatives) (1 of 2), circa 1950-1997 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Mamacoke tract (46 photographs, 26 negatives) (2 of 2), circa 1950-1997 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Natural areas and burn sites, student project (10 photographs), 1976 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Niering site studies (20 photographs, 10 negatives), circa 1957-1962 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Non-arboretum wetlands (2 photos, 1 negative), circa 1970-1976 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Ravine (3 photographs, 2 negatives), 1972 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Right-of-way (43 photographs, 26 negatives) (1 of 3), circa 1954-1970 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Right-of-way (43 photographs, 26 negatives) (2 of 3), circa 1954-1970 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Right-of-way (43 photographs, 26 negatives) (3 of 3), circa 1954-1970 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Small mammal studies (2 photographs, 1 glass plate negative), 1976 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Tidal marsh study, aerial photographs (33 negatives), 1969-1970 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Transect III bud studies (16 photographs, 19 negatives), 1953-1973 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Untitled audio reel; possibly 25th anniversary tape (see series I subseries A folder 8), undated (Box 20, Folder 18)
- Series VIII: Richard Goodwin's historical research of the Arboretum, 1890-1999
  This series contains notes, clippings, drafts, speeches, outlines, maps, correspondence, for writing and speeches regarding the Arboretum produced by Goodwin. This series primarily contains drafts of writing and speeches; and notes and research on the significant families who owned tracts of land that became part of the arboretum. Much of the notes are undated, but contain genealogical trees and lists of dates of ownership. Of particular interest, are maps which capture the development of the Arboretum. See Series II, Land records, for related material on arboretum land holdings; and Series IV Arboretum publications, sub series A for publications on the history of the Arboretum.
  - After the Glacier, drafts, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Alexander purchase, undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Allyn property; includes inventories and notes, undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Arboretum chronology, circa 1999 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Arboretum history docent training, 1996-1997 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Arboretum tracts, texts for bulletin no 32; includes annotations, undated (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Before the Arboretum typescript; includes annotations, undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Bibliographic references, undated (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Bolles, Enoch homestead, undated (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Bolles family notes and research, circa 1973-1989, undated (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Bolles family research; includes photograph of Dr. William Palmer Bolles, undated (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Bolles, Isaiah farm, undated (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Bolles, John chronology, undated (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Bolles, Joseph farm notes, undated (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Bolles, Joshua farm; includes text and family tree, undated (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Bolles, Samuel farm; includes text and map, undated (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Colonial contacts, undated (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Colonial history, 1949-1989 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Connors and Pralevis tract, 1993-1996 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Chronology of New London, undated (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Data for land acquisition table and photos, undated (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Deeds north of Gallows Lane notes, undated (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Drafts, undated (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Eco history of the Connecticut Arboretum, undated (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Eggleston records; includes chronologies, notes, and real estate inventories, undated (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Foxon Lott research, undated (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Gallows Lane, 1988-1997 (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Genealogy various families; includes Bolles, Deshon, Rogers, undated (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Glaciers and vegetation research, 1890, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Harrison's landing and other Benham property, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Hempstead diary notes, undated (Box 22, Folder 2)